Morgan BLEIN

856A 42nd avenue San Francisco, CA 94121 415-230-9012 morganblein@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF SKILLS

Programming: Proficiency with Python, Perl, JMP (SAS), SPSS, and SQL (Oracle, Access), Hadoop and MapReduce.

Secondary programming skills: Knowledge of R, Java, Android, LINUX-UNIX environment, HTML5, CSS3, Shell scripting, STATA and MATLAB.

Basic Software: Expert with Microsoft office (especially Excel) and Google tools on both Mac and PC. **Video and audio:** editing and synthesizing: Adobe CS6 suite, final cut pro X, Audacity, FFMPEG code **Languages**: French (fluent), English (fluent), Spanish (Basic) and Japanese (Basic).

EDUCATION

MS, Business Analytics

California State University, East Bay, CA

July 2016 (Expected)

Cumulative GPA: 3.85

Relevant Coursework: Database Management and Applications (SQL), Data Analytics (Python), Data Warehousing, Prescriptive Analytics, Data Mining, Project Management, Marketing Research and analytics, Advanced Applied Econometrics, SAS programming, Big data applications (Hadoop/Java).

BS, Business Administration, Major: Finance

May 2011

University of San Francisco, San Francisco CA

Honors: Honors Cohort Program of 2011, Member of the National Society of Collegiate Scholars Cumulative GPA: 3.58

Relevant Coursework: Quantitative Methods in Business, Quantitative Business Analysis, Marketing, Analysis of Global Business Conditions, Investment Analysis, Systems in Organization, Financial Institutions & Markets, Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Accounting I and II, and finance electives.

EXPERIENCE

Seyyer

Lead System Integrator

November 2013- July 2015

- Managed cross industry research teams from Japan, Europe and the bay area to create a first of its kind text to video software application, as well as new age text to speech software.
- Create, train and sort through internal databases for voices in 3 different languages, and full-facial animation of several actors, blending artificial intelligence and video to create a product.
- Directly working under the CEO, chief architect and VP of products, responsible for demonstration systems for investors or sales meetings.

Market Research Analyst

September 2011- November 2013

- Use knowledge of economic trends and investigative marketing studies to assist the company's shift between high-tech research to marketable application.
- Use of computer analysis systems to program software processing video data collections, examining various facial features for further application with advertising and entertainment.
- Perform current social research in order to provide the production team with resources for the company to focus on real customer demand (focus groups, surveys, A/B testing)
- Conduct market research on how to vitalize this new technology online using Google analytics or social media channels tools: YouTube, Facebook, and Twitter.

Sidecar

April 2011-September 2011

Marketing Research Contractor

- Conducted market research for the implementation of a rideshare startup in SF.
- Responsible for customer analysis depending on various social, economic and demographic factors in order to build efficient product placement.
- Assisted in creating of the logo, website, name and overall branding of the startup.